{
    "title": "World war-1 Basics",
    "questions": [
 {
    "question": "In which year did World War I begin?",
    "options": ["1914", "1918", "1939", "1920"],
    "correct": "1914"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which event is considered the spark that started World War I?",
    "options": [
      "The sinking of the Titanic",
      "Assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand",
      "Treaty of Versailles",
      "Invasion of Poland"
    ],
    "correct": "Assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which countries were part of the Allied Powers?",
    "options": [
      "Germany, Austria-Hungary, Italy",
      "France, Britain, Russia",
      "Japan, Germany, Italy",
      "USA, Germany, Austria"
    ],
    "correct": "France, Britain, Russia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which weapon was introduced during World War I?",
    "options": ["Atomic bomb", "Tanks", "Missiles", "Jet aircraft"],
    "correct": "Tanks"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the area between opposing trenches called?",
    "options": ["War zone", "Neutral field", "No man's land", "Battlefront"],
    "correct": "No man's land"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country left the war after the 1917 revolution?",
    "options": ["Germany", "Italy", "Russia", "France"],
    "correct": "Russia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the purpose of the League of Nations?",
    "options": [
      "To win World War I",
      "To rebuild Europe",
      "To prevent future wars",
      "To divide territories"
    ],
    "correct": "To prevent future wars"
  },
  {
    "question": "What treaty officially ended World War I?",
    "options": [
      "Treaty of Berlin",
      "Treaty of Versailles",
      "Treaty of London",
      "Treaty of Tordesillas"
    ],
    "correct": "Treaty of Versailles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country joined the war in 1917 and helped tip the balance?",
    "options": ["Spain", "United States", "Japan", "China"],
    "correct": "United States"
  },
  {
    "question": "What global pandemic followed World War I?",
    "options": ["COVID-19", "Spanish Flu", "Black Death", "SARS"],
    "correct": "Spanish Flu"
  }
    ]
}